本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 许块块招不到人悲催包片= =
校对： 许块块    后期： 唱唱反调
好了 我要做的就是
All right, so all I need to do is
填鸡进鸭 再填鸭子进火鸡 然后火鸡鸭
shove the chicken in the duck, the duck in the turkey, and voila...
闪亮登场
Thanksgiving turducken.
这动物填充也太多了吧
That's an alarming amount of animals to stick inside each other.
你能把他们都填进猪里吗?
Can you put it all in a pig?
亲爱的 我回家了!
Honey, I'm home!
你怎么样啊?
How you doin'?
我猜这出是有故事?
So, I'm guessing there is a story here?
当然啦 诡异邻居
There certainly is, wacky neighbor.
我们彻夜未眠 看尼克的晚间生活
We've been up all night, watching a Nick at Nite marathon
感恩节特辑
of Thanksgiving sitcom episodes.
这让我们想在镇里招批现场观众
It made us want a live studio audience for our very own.
观众 哈?
Audience, huh?
我心中夙愿就是能有首歌
I always wished, I had a song that followed me around,
每次我走进房间 它便会奏起
and played everytime I walked into a room.
- 我的歌是... - 蠢主意
- My song would be... - Stupid idea.
夫人 请继续
Wife, continue.
尼克的晚间生活 教会我们
So, Nick at Nite marathon taught us
感恩节是特别的一天
that Thanksgiving is a special day
各种亲戚内讧 厨艺失误
filled with troublemaking in-laws, cooking mishaps,
还有不好的惊喜
and unpleasant surprises.
这也就变成人人嫌弃不想要
Which makes it a holiday which nobody really wanted,
可到头来 人人都需要的节日
but in the end, everyone really needed.
汤姆・派第的美国女孩 将成为我的歌
"American girl" by Tom Petty. That would be my song.
我也不想让你们失望
Well, I hate to disappoint you guys,
但我还是要大胆说一句
but I'm gonna go out on a limb here,
这次感恩节可不会有不好的惊喜
and say there will be no unpleasant surprises this Thanksgiving.
我同意 有的只是家庭的温馨与平和
I agree. There's been a lovely peace in the family.
再说了 我做的饭很简单
Plus, I'm making a foolproof meal.
真的不会出岔子
It literally can't lose.
天啊 我们知道接下来是什么了
Oh, boy! We know what comes next.
什么意思 什么叫...
Whoa, what do you mean? What co...
节日惊喜到
Cue the holiday surprise.
会是谁啊
Who could that be?
去看看 会发生什么事吧
Let's watch and see what happens.
感恩节快乐
Happy Thanksgiving!
是的 我早到了六小时 过会再谈这个
Yes, I'm six hours early. Now we've talked about that.
- 是啊 老爸 早了一会 - 啊
- Yeah, dad, a little early. - Ahh.
- 嘿 多米尼克 - 马蒂
- Hey, Dominick. - Mwah!
特丽莎在哪
Where's Theresa?
不知道
No idea.
经历五十年地狱生活后 我跟她结束了
After almost five miserable decades, I ended it.
我们要离婚了 爷爷要搬来啦
We're getting a divorce. Grandpa's moving in.
不妙哦
Uh-oh!
我喜欢节日特辑
I love holiday episodes.
# 我们来自外太空 定居在新泽西 #
We came from outer space and settled in New Jersey
# 我们取名叫拉里・伯德 #
We took names like Larry Bird
# 和杰西・乔伊娜・柯西 #
and Jackie Joyner-Kersee
# 然后人类搬到隔壁 #
Then the humans moved next door
# 挑战我们的极限 #
Started testing all our limits
# 请坐下来 收看节目 #
So sit right down, enjoy the show
# 半个小时就结束 #
We'll be done in 30 minutes
外星邻居 第二季第九集
你什么意思 老爸 你离开老妈了?
Okay, so, what did you say, dad? You left mom?
心意已决
Like a baby at a fire station.
多米尼克 我们很高兴你来 很高兴
Dominick, we're happy to have you, so happy.
我们很喜欢 可是拜托
We love it. But come on.
为什么要和特丽莎离婚?
Why divorce Theresa?
我们恨彼此
We hate each other.
你们都恨了五十年了 你们喜欢恨彼此啊
You've hated each other for 50 years. You love to hate each other.
仇恨就是你们婚姻的粘合剂
Hate is the glue that keeps your marriage together.
- 爷爷 爷爷 - 感恩节快乐
- Grandpa, Grandpa! - Happy Thanksgiving!
嘿 孩子们
Hey, guys!
奶奶在哪
Where's Grandma?
我离开她了 孩子们 都结束了 她太坏了
I left her, kids. It's over. She's horrible.
她两点到
She'll be here at 2:00.
所以她还会来的
Oh, so she's still coming.
即使你们已经分开? 有意思
Even though you're splitting up? Fun.
当然她要来
Of course she's coming.
我们可不能让那个老骨头独自一人过感恩节
We can't let that crotchety old bag sit alone on Thanksgiving.
我们是一家人
We're family.
现在 孩子们 我要你们带我上楼
Now, kids, I want you to take me upstairs,
给我看看爷爷要睡谁的卧室
and show grandpa whose bedroom he's taking.
- 什么 - 你说什么
- Say what now? - What did you say?
- 走吧 - 你恨我的卧室
- Let's go. - You'd hate my bedroom!
- 我还尿床 - 不 你才不呢
- I still pee the bed! - No, you don't!
我现在就去尿
I'm going to as soon as I get up there.
- 你老爸可不能搬进来 - 当然不能
- So, your father's not moving in here. - Of course not.
因为让那个男人来我们家
Because fitting that man in our house
就像填鸭子进火鸡
is kind of like fitting this duck into this turkey.
别担心 宝贝 他不会久留
Don't worry. Babe, he's not staying.
我妈是个病态的人
My mother is a damaged person
她需要有发泄对象
who needs someone to scream at.
我老爸身边需要有病态的人
My father needs a damaged person around,
这样他才有优越感
so he can feel superior.
相信我 分手不会持久的
Believe me, there's no way this breakup will last.
那倒是
True.
如果说我们从节日特辑里学到什么的话
If there's one thing we learned from our holiday-episode research,
那就是在节日最后 一切
it's that things will always go back to normal
都会回归正常
at the end of the holiday.
没错 他们想让你认为一切不可收拾
Yes. They try to trick you into thinking that they won't,
其实他们也不想改变节目根基
but they don't want to change the premise of the show.
要是你爸搬进来 根基就变了
Well, this premise will change if your father moves in,
因为我会跳进烤箱
'cause then I'm getting in the oven with the poultry.
迪克 我们的观众在车库
Dick, our audience is in the garage.
我和爸爸聊天的时候 你去逗逗他们吧
Would you please entertain them while I have a chat with dad?
没人尊重我的打毛衣时间
Does no one respect my knitting time?
夫君 我不喜欢马蒂他们家
Oh, husband, I do not enjoy how the story has become
故事发展走向
about the Mertzes over there.
我们是主要家庭 他们是怪异邻居
We are the main family. They are the wacky neighbors.
我们应该有自己的感恩节故事
We deserve a thanksgiving story of our own,
而不是一堆让他们感恩节更有意思的笑话
Not just a bunch of jokes that makes their story funnier.
你有什么主意?
So, what are you thinking?
我们去高速生产线找个工作
Perhaps we get a job in a high-speed assembly line.
好主意
Ooh! Good one.
带回流浪汉 帮他清洁
Or bring home a homeless man, clean him up,
让他当大公司老总
and make him the C.E.O. of a major corporation.
太棒了
Great.
或者我们和孩子们交换
Or we could trade responsibilities with the children
学些好玩却有意义的事
in order to learn comical, and yet mutually beneficial lessons.
你认为当大人很难吗
You think being a grown-up is hard?
试试当小孩吧
Try being a kid sometime.
我太太说结婚纪念日
My wife said that for our anniversary,
她要去她从未去过的地方
she wanted to go somewhere she's never been before,
我说 那不如去厨房吧
so I said, "Try the kitchen."
怎么样啊 亲爱的
How we doing on time, sweetie?
烤炉里六小时
Six hours in the oven.
还有三分之二的肉是生的
I still got two out of the three animals uncooked.
好像大的在保护小的一样
It's like the bigger one is protecting the littler ones.
让它们煮熟啊!
Let them burn!
尽量快点吧 以我的经验
Well, try and speed it up, 'cause in my experience,
我爸妈吃东西的时候 不太吵架
my parents fight less when they have food in their mouths.
你老妈可要抱怨了
Your mother's gonna be a basket case.
煮熟啊 科学怪人
Cook, you unholy Frankenstein!
- 煮熟 - 拜托
- Cook! - Come on!
我们会好好的
We're gonna be okay.
但你和奶奶
But you and Grandma?
我们都爱你俩
I loved you two together.
那怎么会发生 你们是灵魂伴侣啊
How is this even possible? You two are soul mates.
我不知道 我一直觉得你们俩恨彼此
I don't know. I always thought you two sort of hated each other.
这才是我的孙女嘛
Now, that's my granddaughter.
孩子 别伤心了
And, kid, don't be sad.
你知道上周我在汉普顿客栈
You know what I've been doing this last week
房间里干了什么吗
in my room at the Hampton Inn?
床上吃喝 微笑
Eating in bed and smiling.
自从我结婚 这两样都没干过
I haven't done either since I got married.
可你们走过人生三分之二了啊
But you were together for two-thirds of a human life span.
为什么现在分开
Why now?
我受够了
Eh, it was enough.
我有个新丧夫的数学老师
I got a recently widowed math teacher.
虽说她有个爆炸头
She's got a weird Jewfro thing going on,
可人不丑
But she's not hideous.
- 你要我撮合吗 - 当然 我来者不拒
- You want me to set it up? - Sure. I'm open.
把我在汉普顿的电话给她
Give her my number at the Hamp.
天啊 奶奶来了
Oh, boy. There's Grandma.
现在 她要展开泪水攻势换取同情心了
Now, she's gonna be pulling all the waterworks with sympathy.
孩子们 可不要上当
But, kids, don't fall for it.
好了 老爸 对她好点
All right, dad. Just please be nice to her.
上帝啊 求她对我好点
God, please let her be nice to me.
- 甜心 - 嘿
- Sweetheart! - Hey!
感恩节快乐
Happy Thanksgiving!
- 你好 亲爱的 - 你好 感恩节快乐
- Aw! Hello, honey. - Happy Thanksgiving. Hello.
- 你闻起来不错哦 - 噢
- Mm! Don't you smell good? - Oh.
家里看起来很棒嘛
And the house looks gorgeous.
真的吗 谢谢你
Really? Thank you.
你头发又长又好 皮肤还有点小麦色
Wow. Your hair's all nice and long, and you look tan.
这周去晒的
Hit the spa this week.
我弄了铜色 接了发
I am bronzed and hair-extended,
还脱了毛 我都不知道那种地方还脱毛
and waxed in places I had no idea people wax.
现在我们知道了
Well, now we have that information.
好嘞 我想喝点酒了
Okay. I'm ready for some wine.
昨晚桑巴舞泡沫派对有点太疯狂啦
The foam party at La Bamba got a little crazy last night,
说不定我还吃了狗毛
And I could use some hair of the dog.
- 多米尼克 - 特丽莎
- Dominick. - Theresa.
猜猜谁不小心舞会上约了两个人
Guess who's accidentally got two dates to the prom?
我永不忘记
I'll never get away with it.
我们错过了什么
What did we miss?
我不知道
I don't know.
晚餐闻起来很香
Oh, dinner smells mouth-watering.
我不知道以前说过这句话没
Now, I don't know if I've ever told you this,
你做饭不错
but I think you're a wonderful cook.
你没说过
You haven't.
你从没说过 从没有
You haven't ever said that, like never.
老妈 我要说
You know, ma, I got to say,
你好多年都没有这么有精神了
you haven't looked this good in years.
我很欣慰
Well, I should hope so.
我减了肥
I've lost a lot of weight.
准确的说是 二百一十磅
210 pounds of soul-sucking fat, to be exact.
太好笑了
Hardy har.
我在商场和其他单身老人
Oh, plus, I've been power-walking at the mall
一起暴走
with other senior singles.
我有说脱毛吗?
And did I mention the wax?
是说过了 绝对说过了
Yes, you did. You definitely did.
马斯克 带你妹妹上楼去
Max, take your sister upstairs.
你看起来真美 奶奶
You look pretty, Grandma.
谢谢你 小甜心
Oh, thank you, sweetheart.
记住 婚姻会毁了你容颜
Now, remember, marriage ruins your looks.
不 别记住 快走吧
Nope. Don't remember that. Go.
老妈 你一人住在大房子里干吗呢
So, ma, what are you gonna do in that big house all alone?
可能会卖掉
Probably sell it.
那 我的房间怎么办
Well, then, what's... what's gonna happen to my room?
哪个是你的房间
Which one was your room?
我的工艺室还是瑜伽室?
My craft room or the yoga room?
从你卧室往进走到走廊尽头
It's the one down the hall from your bedroom
这样我晚上害怕的时候 你就能听到了
so you could hear me in case I got scared during the night.
瑜伽室啊
Ah. Yoga room.
看看我们坐在这沉默
Look at us just sitting here in silence.
我们是什么 多余的? 做点事
What are we, extras? Do something.
我是同性恋
I'm gay.
我就知道
I knew it.
好了 伙计们 我能和家人单独呆会吗
All right, guys, can I have a moment alone with my family, please?
再次声明 我发现你们社会
For the record, I find it very regrettable
一大遗憾就是
that your primitive society
亲戚家庭里地位不高
Doesn't place a higher value on in-laws.
合法第三方也一样
Or legitimate third-party candidates.
再会
See you guys.
天啊
Oh, boy.
我的相亲资料又有点击者了
Another hit on my online dating profile.
哇 他挺帅的嘛 才六十岁
Oh, now, he's a cutie, and he's still in his 60s.
亲娘啊 别跟我说你注册了
For God's sake, don't tell me you've signed up
相亲网站
with one of those online dating scams.
是啊 这种交易就是我付二十美元
Yep. It's the kind of scam where I give them 20 bucks
他们还我激情澎湃的性生活
and they give me a revitalized sex life.
- 噢 - 拜托 两位
- Oh! - Oh, come on, guys.
只是虚张声势罢了 你根本没在约会啊
This is just posturing. You're not dating already.
是啊 你们俩没分手嘛
Right, because you guys aren't breaking up. Right?
幸好我那个年代
It's a good thing they didn't have online dating
没有相亲网站 不然还得
when I was younger or I would have needed
给刚刚脱毛的地方复原
A what-I-just-had-waxed transplant.
是啊 把纸巾扔掉
Oh, sure. Throw the tissue away.
反正还有很多嘛
There's plenty of snot-free real estate.
不 你就是乐意扔掉
No, you just want to throw it away,
换新的 崭新的
and move on to a fresh, new one.
实话 我乐意
That's true. I do.
雷吉 我实话实话了
Reggie, I'm gonna go out on a limb,
这只是我爷爷奶奶的事
and say that this is about my grandparents.
你说得对
You're right.
我生气是因为我跟察布隆的灵魂伴侣分手
I'm mad because I blew off my Zabvronian soul mate,
她可保证爱我永远 你却没有
who's guaranteed to love me forever, for you.
你很乐意两个人分手
You seem so happy about two people breaking up,
即使他们过了五十年
even after 50 years.
我知道他们压力很大
I know it's stressful,
但是你要和人类在一起
but if you're gonna be with a human,
你就要接受我们的不可预计性
You have to accept the fact that we're unpredictable.
半数以上的婚姻终结 这是事实
More than 50% of marriages end. That's just reality.
一半
50%.
人类是始乱终弃的禽兽
Humans are inconstant monsters.
我跟禽兽在约会
I'm dating a monster.
当然 琥珀 就跟隔壁外星人约会吧
Sure, Amber. Just date the weird alien kid next door.
会很有意思的
It'll be fun.
天啊
Oh, God.
我的烤箱搞不定这些尸体
My oven can't handle this many corpses.
来真的了 黛比
This is real, deb.
我爸妈真要分开了
My parents are splitting up for real.
他们要不和好
If they don't get back together,
我就是个家庭破碎的孩子
that makes me the child of a broken home.
我不想当孤儿
I don't want to be an orphan.
亲爱的 我懂 尽管你把孤儿定义弄错了
Oh, honey, I know, although that's not what an orphan is.
我觉得你应该对此
You know, I think you could be getting
更伤心一些 黛比
a little more upset here, Deb.
你知道离婚家庭的孩子
Did you know that children of divorce
自己也趋向于离婚吗
are more likely to divorce themselves?
这也许跟你的未来息息相关
This could have serious implications on your future.
不管发生什么 那个男人别想搬进来
Okay, well, whatever happens, that man is not moving in here.
马蒂 你的计划是什么
Marty, what's your plan?
好嘞 真是个好主意
Oh, right. That's a good idea.
让孩子对爸妈的幸福
Make it the responsibility of the child
负担起责任
to keep his parents together.
你知道这有多可怕吗
Do you know how detrimental that could be?
对一个四十三岁的大人来说?
To a 43-year-old man?
亲爱的 此时此刻
Well, honey, at a moment like this,
任何人都会像孩子般受伤无助的
every man becomes a hurt, helpless little boy.
少废话!
Stop your blubbering!
我们路过想让你们别太担心
We just wanted to pop by to remind you not to worry.
感恩节晚餐一过
This is a completely manufactured crisis
这些复杂的问题便会自己解决的
which will resolve itself by the end of Thanksgiving dinner.
要是你想快点结束
Although, if you'd like it resolved sooner,
我们很乐意帮忙啊
We're happy to pull some hijinks.
因为这才是主演的戏份嘛
Because that's what main characters do!
考虑下吧
Think about it.
天啊
Oh, God.
看看你们
Just look at you guys.
还有曾经的火花 对吗
You still got that same old spark, you know?
我想知道你怎么还有
Well, I would like to know where you even
钱买那个手机
came up with the cash for that phone.
你的合约还有一年呢
You had at least another year on your contract!
我只不过用了结婚纪念日
I just used the money I was gonna waste
要送礼物的钱
on your anniversary present.
好主意啊
Great idea, sister.
我要花钱买瓶
I think I'll spend my wad on a bottle
那些蓝色药丸
of those little, blue pills.
要知道 我们这年纪女性可是十倍多于男性
You know, the gals outnumber the fellas 10 to 1 at our age.
等不及想看看
Can't wait to meet the lucky broad
哪位好运气把自己余生都摊到
who gets stuck having to listen to you snore
听你打鼾了
for the rest of her life.
孩子们 吃饭啦
Kids, dinner!
来吃饭吧 今天要结束了 大家都各回各家
Come eat now so this day can end and everyone can go home
不许呆在我家
to their house that isn't this one.
有人见我夫人了吗
Has anyone seen my wife?
她要错过鸡鸭火鸡连环塞的美味了
She's going to miss this revolting bird-on-bird-on-bird action.
黛比用了你的填料方哦 老妈
Debbie used your stuffing recipe, Mom.
老爸 你的最爱啊
Dad, that's your favorite, right?
跟老妈讲讲你最爱了
Tell Mom how that's your favorite.
我从不喜欢她的填料
I never liked her stuffing.
那是因为做的太美了 你个白痴
That's because it's too good for you, you nincompoop.
注意措辞
Watch your language.
这可不是你去的乱酒吧
This isn't one of your sailor hump-hump bars.
伺候他吧 黛比
Oh! Enjoy him, Debbie.
不不 你伺候他
No, no. You enjoy him.
你把他带回家 你伺候他吧
You take him home, and you enjoy him.
我再也不能忍了 黛比
I really can't tolerate this anymore, Deborah.
这可是你灵魂伴侣的父母
These are the parents of your soul mate.
这神圣的关系是要敬畏的
That is a sacred bond that deserves mad respect.
宣言
Announcement!
我发现故事主线了
I found us a story line.
你好
Hello!
你好啊
Hi, there.
我们是杰西・乔伊娜・柯西的父母
We are the parents of Jackie Joyner-Kersee,
是那位的岳父和岳母
and we are the in-laws to that guy.
广告时间 广告...
Cut to commercial. Cut to commer...
不敢相信他们让我来儿童桌就餐
I can't believe they stuck me at the kids' table.
迪克 你喜欢老人吗
So, Dick, you like old people, huh?
我发现他们很有性格
I find they have character,
有历史 超级会打毛线
history, and superior knitting skills.
更别提超酷的味道了
Not to mention that cool smell.
那你愿意和你自己
How would you like a chance
专属的老人分享一间卧室吗
to have your very own old person living right in your room?
这也太棒了吧
Doesn't that sound amazing?
我的专属老人 美梦啊
My very own old person? What a dream.
孩子们 我的智商比你们高五十倍
Guys, my I.Q. is more than 50 times greater than yours.
你们以为这样就能把我骗到吗
Did you really think you could manipulate me like that?
不妨一试嘛
Uh, it was worth a try.
拉我的手指
Pull my finger.
抱歉 臣妾做不到啊
I'm sorry. I can't do this.
杰西的爸妈也来了真好啊
It is so nice to have Jackie's parents here.
有个缓冲也不错
Kind of nice to have a buffer.
谢谢你们 马蒂 黛比・韦弗
Well, thank you, Marty and Debbie Weaver,
用你自己辛苦工作的血汗钱在你家
For hosting us in your home that you paid for
招待我们
from the sweat of your brow.
好嘞 又来了
Okay. Here we go.
你想说什么 岳父
So what are you saying, father-in-law,
没有我爸资助 我不能负担自己的生活方式吗
that I can't afford my lifestyle without my father's trust fund?
他可不是这个意思 夫君
He's not saying that at all, husband.
我可爱的女儿说得对
My lovely daughter is right.
我可没那样说过 没说一次
I have not said that, not once.
其他人却这样议论
Other people have said it.
他们议论纷纷 不是我们
They've said it a lot. But not us.
还有我没说过的就是你们家
Another thing we don't say is that your family fortune
收入都是别人辛苦挣来的
is mostly blood money taken from the people...
我们一生致力于帮助的人
People we have devoted our lives to helping.
你们两位从哪来的?
Where are you guys from again?
- 法国 - 加拿大
- France. - Canada.
你最好小心我老公
Oh, you better watch out for my husband.
他讨厌外国人
He hates foreigners.
自己去牙买加旅游
This from the woman who kept her wallet
把钱藏在内衣下的女人 还有脸说我
in her underwear during our entire Jamaican cruise.
我希望你满意了 岳父母们
I hope you're satisfied, in-laws.
你们让这顿感恩节晚宴
You've turned this Thanksgiving meal
混乱不堪 冲突不断
into chaos and conflict.
一如既往 毒药功效
As always, you're toxic.
放轻松 拉里
Easy, Larry.
尊重都去哪了
Yeah, what happened to respecting,
视岳父母为亲生父母的承诺呢 拉里
and loving your in-laws as your own, Larry?
我承诺时 杰西的父母
When I said that, Jackie's parents
还有他们比汝等神圣的态度
and their holier-than-thou attitude
都在宇宙另一边好好藏着呢
were safely ensconced on the other side of the Universe.
夫君 假装的私人耳语不奏效
Husband, fake private whispering does not work.
拉里也没用
Neither does Larry.
- 毒药 - 她是毒药?
- Toxic! - She's toxic?
这位现在就像穿小鞋跑长跑
This one over here is like Three Mile Island in sensible shoes.
吃你的饭 禽兽
Keep stuffing your face, animal.
现在墓地买一送一
You've got side-by-side grave plots now.
看啊 看你你来我往 唇枪舌战
Come on! Look at that repartee, huh?
为什么你想离开这个家庭呢
Why would you want to walk away from that, from this family?
为什么
Why?
别离开你家
Or your lovely house.
既然你都把房贷还了
Now that you finally paid off that mortgage,
你的草坪动物也深得你心
and your lawn animals are just the way you like them.
我们家没有草坪动物
Our house doesn't even have lawn animals.
各位 我只想说我以你们为自豪
Guys, I just want to say I'm proud of you.
许多人就认命这么不开心了
Most people would just settle for being unhappy,
要解除五十年的婚约需要勇气
but it takes some serious sack to break up after 50 years
看看你们能不能活得更好 太棒了
to see if there's a better life out there, so mazel tov.
琥珀 你怎么能这么说
Amber, how could you say that?
我希望我能和一个人幸福快乐到永远
Well, I hope that I'm happy with one person forever,
但若事与愿违 我想和爷爷奶奶一样勇敢
but if not, I'd like to be as brave as my grandparents.
容我先走一步
May I please be excused?
我也能先走吗
May I also be excused?
- 哦 - 我跟他聊聊
- Oh. - I'll talk to him.
好的 去跟我儿子交心谈谈
Oh, yes. Go have a heart to heart with our son.
这是你强项
That's your strong suit.
你太会说笑了
You're such a delight.
你们知道我是相信直觉的人吗
Do you know I'm very intuitive?
我做了很多能量工作
I've done lots of energy work,
我能感受到家里的麻烦事
and I sense some trouble in the home.
出人意料 天才啊
Wow. You think, genius?
老妈 你听到我找到工作了吗
So, Mommy, did you hear that I got a job?
不 我什么都没听到
No. I can't hear anything
拉里一直强词夺理
over Larry's deafening sense of entitlement.
不好意思
Oh, I'm sorry.
你胡扯八道的时候 我也没听清
I couldn't hear you over your deafening sense of sucking.
杰西 抱歉先走了
Jackie, um, if you'll excuse me,
让你和你家人先处理问题吧
I'm gonna let you deal with your family drama.
我去看看我的家人
I'm gonna go check on mine.
你们不喝酒 那...
You guys don't drink wine, so...
雷吉 你让不让我进
Reggie, are you gonna let me in?
别烦我 禽兽啊
Leave me alone, you monster!
儿子 你还好吗
Son, are you okay?
开门 马蒂
Open up, Marty.
走开 你不在乎我
Go away! You don't care about me!
你伤了我的心 你根本不在乎
You hurt my feelings, and you don't care!
我还是先安抚孩子吧
I'm gonna start with the actual child.
雷吉 半数以上的人离婚是很糟
Reggie, it stinks that half of all people get divorced,
可你不能确定爱会持久啊
and that you can't be sure that love will last forever,
可这让持久的爱才弥足珍贵 不是吗
but that's what makes it so amazing when it does, right?
你们俩 当然你们不相爱了
And you two, of course you fell out of love.
因为你们不努力去爱了
'Cause you stopped working at it.
这可是日积月累的细功夫
It takes work every single day.
没有绝对 雷吉 要靠你辛苦经营
There are no guarantees, Reggie, so you have to work at it.
即使过了五十年 一辈子
Even after 50 years, or it dies.
一辈子的经营才让一切多么美好
And it's that work that makes it beautiful.
太美了 黛比・韦弗
That was lovely, Debbie Weaver.
谢谢 雷吉
Well, thanks, Reg.
肺腑之言 借酒而发
It was from the heart... And the wine.
我们还好吗
So, are we okay?
琥珀 你知道历史课的标志
Amber, you know the sign in history class
记载道"努力赢取自由"
that says "Work sets you free."?
说的就是我们
It's about us.
其实是说大屠杀 不过我懂你
It's actually a Holocaust diorama, but I hear you.
我喜欢要和你共度每一天
I like that we're gonna have to spend every single day
一起经营我们的爱情 至死不渝
of our lives working to keep our love alive.
你确定?
Are you sure?
简根本不需要经营
Jane wouldn't be any work at all.
任何值得的事都需要努力
Anything worthwhile takes work.
那你们俩呢
And what about you two?
你们真的愿意重头再来吗
Do you seriously want to start over now?
我们重战桃花场
We go back out there,
大家都期待我们人模人样的
people are gonna want us to work on ourselves.
我每天都要刮胡子
I'm gonna have to shave every day,
收腹提臀 冲厕所
suck in my gut, flush.
可不是
Tell me about it.
你知道弄成这样要多辛苦嘛
You know how tiring it is to get all fapitzed like this?
你看起来真美 韦弗太太
You look great, Mrs. Weaver.
住嘴 我讨厌有氧运动和脱毛
Stop. I hate cardio. I hate getting waxed.
我讨厌这手机的铃声
I hate the stupid noises that phone makes,
更讨厌把它带身上
and I hate having to hold in my toots.
是啊
Yeah.
我更愿意跟你谈天 过一辈子
I'd rather phone it in and die with you
而不是跟一些想让我锻炼的脑残过
than some broad who wants me to work for the rest of my life.
# 我守护你 我守护你 #
I got you, I got you
过来 你个混蛋
Come here, you stinker.
特丽莎
Theresa.
# 我守护你 我守护你 我守护你 #
I got you, I got you, I got you, I got you
这么说 你们俩和好了?
So, does this mean that you guys are back together?
为了最恼人的理由
For the most depressing reason imaginable.
好消息 各位
Great news, everybody!
我爸妈和好如初啦
My mom and dad are back together!
- 太棒了 - 是吧 我就知道
- Yay! - See? I knew it.
节日最后 一切都会好的
Things always go back to normal at the end of the holiday.
这倒提醒我了 临近晚上九点
Oh! Which reminds me, it's nearly 9:00 P.M.
我宝贵的岳父母 你们还要搭虫洞回去吧
My precious in-laws, I believe you have a wormhole to catch.
家乡许多和平事务要处理
Plenty of peace rallies back home to attend.
我猜你很乐意送我们走
I bet you would love to see us leave so soon,
可我们有一辈子东西还没打开
but we have a lifetime of possessions to unpack.
打开?
Unpack?
是的 很显然 你们家需要我们
Yes, it's clear that your family needs us
比你父亲战后的孤儿还可怜
more than even the orphans your father's war created.
我们要留下
So we're staying.
宇宙里再没比扶你们家
There is no bigger charity case in the Universe
更迫切的扶贫项目了
right now than you, son.
恭喜啊
Congratulations.
天啊
Oh, God.
他们不走了
They're not leaving.
# 我守护你 #
I got you
还是个"未完待续"
This is a "to be continued".
一切都太棒啦
Things are gonna be so great now
爸妈和好如初啦
that Mom and Dad are back together.
我知道 亲爱的
I know, honey.
既然一切都好了 我们应该
You know, we really ought to spend more time with them
多花点时间跟他们相处
now that things are all better.
我们应该带他们去迪士尼玩
We should take a trip with them to Disney World!
全家都去 喜气洋洋一家人
All of us, just one big, happy family.
好诶!
Fun!
# 他们若要跌倒 #
If they all fall down
# 你依旧有我 我陪你在侧 #
you still got me and I got you
# 我守护你 我守护你 #
I got you, I got you
# 我守护你 我守护你 我守护你 #
I got you, I got you, I got you, I got you
谢谢你 迪克
Thank you, Dick.
# 我守护你 我守护你 #
I got you, I got you
你没错 宝贝
You're right, babe.
今早的火鸡鸭更美味了
The turducken is even better the morning after.
我今年真是得了你妈填料的真传
And I really nailed your mom's stuffing recipe this year.
你们好
Buon giorno.
我找特丽莎
I am here for Theresa.
找谁
Excuse me.
我们在网上认识 我今天来接她吃早午餐
We met online, and I am-a supposed to pick her up here for brunch.
她永远名花有主啦
Well, she's unavailable like forever.
- 她跟我爸和好了 - 我很遗憾
- She went back with my dad. - I am so sorry to hear this.
我是家财万贯 坐拥世界
I am a man who has all the money in the world,
却无人分享
But-a nobody to share it with.
不好意思
Mi scusi.
当我看到她资料 我以为我...
But when I saw her profile, I thought to myself this...
我能与这个女人共度垂暮之年
This is the woman I could spend my twilight years
环游世界
traveling the world with.
天啊
God.
我们就不能把她电话给他吗?
I mean, would it kill us to pass along her phone number?
给你
Here.
噢
Oh!
谢谢
Grazie.
不客气
Prego.
- 够了 西班牙佬 - 哥们 别介啊
- All right, Don Juan. - Oh, no. Carmine.